<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="SignalSmith" inherits="RefCounted" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Performs time-stretching and pitch-shifting on raw audio buffers using Signalsmith.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		SignalSmith is a low-level audio processing utility which wraps the Signalsmith time-stretching library. It operates on raw interleaved floating-point PCM audio buffers and allows independent control of playback tempo and pitch.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="change_tempo">
			<return type="AudioStreamWAV" />
			<param index="0" name="path" type="String" />
			<param index="1" name="tempo" type="float" />
			<param index="2" name="pitch" type="float" default="1.0" />
			<description>
				Loads an MP3 file, applies time-stretching and pitch-shifting using the Signalsmith engine, and returns a streamable AudioStreamWAV.
				The `tempo` parameter controls playback speed without affecting pitch. A value of `1.0` preserves the original speed.
				The `pitch` parameter is a transpose factor. A value of `1.0` preserves pitch, `2.0` raises pitch by one octave,
				and `0.5` lowers pitch by one octave.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="process">
			<return type="PackedFloat32Array" />
			<param index="0" name="input" type="PackedFloat32Array" />
			<description>
				Processes a block of interleaved audio samples and returns a new buffer containing the time-stretched and pitch-shifted result.
				The effective playback speed is determined by the ratio of input samples to output samples, as influenced by the current tempo setting. The input buffer must contain 32-bit floating-point PCM data and be interleaved according to the configured channel count.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="reset">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Resets the internal processing state.
				This should be called when restarting playback or discontinuously changing input streams.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_channels">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="channels" type="int" />
			<description>
				Sets the number of audio channels.
				Input and output buffers are expected to be interleaved according to this channel count.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_pitch">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="pitch" type="float" />
			<description>
				Sets the pitch transpose factor.
				A value of `1.0` leaves pitch unchanged. Values greater than `1.0` raise pitch, while values less than `1.0` lower pitch.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_sample_rate">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="rate" type="int" />
			<description>
				Sets the sample rate, in Hz, used by the internal processing engine.
				Changing the sample rate resets the internal state.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_tempo">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="tempo" type="float" />
			<description>
				Sets the tempo multiplier used during processing.
				This value influences the ratio between input and output buffer sizes during time-stretching. A value of `1.0` preserves the original tempo, values greater than `1.0` speed up playback, and values less than `1.0` slow it down.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
